Jacob Imsande

Pawleys Island, SC 29585 / 423.930.0290 jacob@jacobimsande.com

Professional Summary

Excel in leadership, organization, planning, multi tasking, time management, unyielding ethics, and morals. Leadership roles have been rewarded due to exceptional performance which has led to excellent reviews. Organization and planning are two skill sets that allow for timely deadlines consistently being met ahead of schedule. High expectations from employers and professors are often exceeded through a diligent work ethic and acute execution. Multi-tasking is an area that is often challenged, however regularly surpassed by balancing a difficult class workload while working 10 to 15 hours weekly outside the classroom. Time management is a crucial element, challenging time constraints with performance, both are connected to professional and scholastic development. Ethics and morals are the most important qualities to possess, having been raised in an environment where they were taught by example provided an exceptional opportunity to excel both in college and professionally. These skills combined with strong computer software knowledge and personal maturation offer a solid foundation to build upon.

Education

Clemson University

May – 2023

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science

An insurmountable amount of knowledge was gained by achieving a 3.57 GPA and 122 credit hours at graduation. Various Programming classes taught the importance to deliver under pressure, time constraint deadlines, and integral detail maturation. Another crucial learning aspect was gained through Software Engineering courses with an emphasis gained by developing a sense of "real time" understanding from repetitive opportunities for personal maturation being challenged and put to the test dealing with confrontations and complexities of knowing how to act and react. All these classes and many more have proven to be invaluable in and out of the classroom and will transfer directly into the workplace.

Relevant Experience

Pawleys Island Presbyterian Church Computer and Media Engineer Intern

Manage the audio and visual systems for all church services. Create programs as needed to increase functionality.

The Original Benjamins Calabash Seafood

5/2021 - 8/2021

5/2022 - Present

Host / Server

Developed professional and personal traits through the interaction of internal and external customers and managers.

FUEL Travel 5/2020 – 8/2020

Remote Lead Developer Intern

Performed in a Lead role developing a tool to simulate the booking of hotel rooms using JavaScript.

Deroma's Pizza 5/2019 – 8/2019

Kitchen Prep

Assisted in all preparations for customer orders as well as performing multiple other tasks assigned by management.

Technical and Computer Skills

Docker – Software Languages (C/C++, Java, Python, JavaScript, HTML, CSS)

Operating Systems (Windows, Apple IOS, macOS, Linux/Unix) – Computer Science I&II – Git
Cloud Computing – Amazon Web – Oracle Cloud – Google Cloud – Algorithms and Data Structures
Network Programming – Engineering & API's – Cloud Computing and Software Development Foundations

Leadership Activities and Training

Rise (Residents in Science and Engineering) – Fellowship of Christian Athletes
Reformed University Fellowship (RUF) – Clemson University Makerspace – Latin Club
Science Hill Robotics Team: Drive Team Captain and Programmer – FCA Spring Mission Trip
PIPC IT Engineer – Teach My People Tutor – Autism Society of America Tutor – At Risk Youth Mentor